#### **RESUME**

#### **DILIP KUMAR NUNE**

dilipkumarn6@gmail.com +91-7989628319.

### **Summary:**

B.Tech(IT) with 5+ years of experience in IT Industry with rich experience in Overseas Client Handling, System, Server & Network Administration, Site Connectivity (LAN, WAN, and VPN), Managing across 7 plus sites, Vendor Management of 5 plus vendors, IT governance, Cyber Security.

### **Specialties:**

Mail Servers, Email Security, Data Security, Team Management, Licensing Management, overseas Clients management, VOIP Phones Network Design, Azure portals management, office 365, Site Connectivity, Windows Server, Linux server, Vendor Management, MIS, Project Management, System Administration, Firewall Management, Azure Active Directory Administration, Anti-virus Management, Compliance Management, Asset Management, IT governance,

### Areas of Expertise:

- Solve IT-related critical problems, new system studies, etc.
- Office 365 Global Administration.
- Firewall Administration.
- Centralized Antivirus Administration.
- Azure Active Directory Administration.
- Technical Up-gradation Analysis of various Systems (H/W, S/W, Application Software, Network)
- Implementing Cyber Security to Prevent Cyber-attack like Ransomware.
- Coordinate for New Technology implementation.
- System Administration Monitoring of the Unit's Systems on a day-to-day basis.
- Ensure User's satisfaction and their further requirement.
- Data Centre Management (Network, Servers, Firewall etc.)
- Train End Users for smooth handling of the Application Systems.

•

## **Vendor Management:**

- Negotiation with vendors for on-time delivery of quality IT products at the best price.
- Appraise vendor's performance and develop new vendors.

### **Experience:**

# IT-EXECUTIVE- IT Infra (Arunachala Logistics Pvt Ltd. Hyderabad, TS) FEB2021 – Current

- Designs, plans, and implements system and network architectures that are high-performing, scalable, fault-tolerant, secure, and compliant.
- Plan, coordinate, supervise, and manage day-to-day computer activities related to the systems and software applications' design, development, implementation, and troubleshooting.
- Forti Mail Cloud, Barracuda email security administration, monitoring the process of identifying phishing attacks in their early stages, warning users and administrators, ideally mitigating the threat, and making sure our domains are maintained and regularly updated.
- Configuring multiple firewalls and administration, firewall policies, static routes, VPN, and administration.
- Microsoft Office 365 Global Administration.
- Email ID creations and Managing MFA in Office 365, Maintaining exchange online protection in Office 365.
- Creating inbound and outbound anti-spam rules.
- Creating mail flow rules in EOP, troubleshooting mail flow issues, Managing Microsoft Defender, and Managing alerts and rules.
- Administration of Bitdefender antivirus gravity zone.
- Creating policies for user groups, content filters, device controls, monitoring and generating reports
- Attending to day-to-day user's problems. Wi-Fi router configuration and administration.
- Configuring and maintaining the file server.
- Designing, implementing, and maintaining of Windows-based Network.
- Microsoft Office 365 support. Procurement of IT assets and vendor management.
- Administration of ILL, MPLS, and Broadband connections in all the branches.
- Accounting and bill processing for IT infra. Network administration.
- Giving system and network support to the branches as well. Biometric device installation and smart office administration.
- Provide support and guidance for the Enterprise Infrastructure environment.
- New office Setup (ILL installation, Network design, server install).
- Coordinate with Sites Head for Data Storage System and Data security system etc.
- Automative weight machine systems support.
- Azure Active directory administration.

# SYSTEM ENGINEER- IT (PRECISION INFORMATIC(M) PVT LTD) CLIENT:AUROBINDO PHARMA LTD HYDERABAD AUG 2019 –JUN 2020

- Provide leadership, vision, and management to the IT department
- Configuring & maintaining windows domain server 2003/2008.

- Microsoft Office 365 Global Administration.
- Email id creations, Distribution lists creation in office 365. Managing MFA in office 365.
- Maintaining exchange online protection in office 365. Creating inbound and outbound antispam rules.
- Creating mail flow rules in EOP. Troubleshoot mail flow issues. Managing Microsoft Defender.
- Managing alerts and rules. Installation & maintenance service packs and Symantec antivirus.
- Attending day-to-day user problem. Configuration of WSUS (Windows server update services).
- Configuration of DHCP and DNS. Configuring and maintaining of file server.
- Run data backup for users regularly.
- Designing, implementing and maintaining a Windows-based Network.
- Configuring & Troubleshooting IPS signatures, Gateway Antivirus, Filtering the websites using SonicWall Content Filter. Configuring and Troubleshooting Bandwidth Management on SonicWall.
- Configuration of Symantec Endpoint Protection Manager 12.0.
- Managing Computer Groups & Clients in Symantec. Configuration Manage Clients & Unmanaged Clients in Symantec. Managing domains and administrator accounts in Symantec.
- Configuring client installation package using Symantec.
- Updating definitions and content( About Live Update Policies).
- Network Printer Configurations. Lan & Wan Monitoring (Using PRTG).
- Zoom meeting administration. Supporting video conferencing through zoom, Microsoft teams, etc.

# IT-ENGINEER (EAGLE INFRA INDIA Ltd Hyderabad, TS) MARCH 2017 – JUNE 2018

- Managing Day to Day IT Support to through-out the organization.
- Installation & maintaining and attending day-to-day user's problem calls.
- Users & Group Management. Designing, implementation and maintenance of Windows based Network, Connecting to Remote System using Terminal Service. Configuration of DHCP.
- Checking Windows software updates and anti virus signature update on client computers.
- Installation and updating of operating system and other software.
- Networking Hardware & Software support. LAN Networking (Client Side), WANS monitoring.
- Network Printer Configuration. Creating E-Mail Accounts in Mail Server.
- Applying Storage Quotas on user Mailbox. Accessing Mailbox using Outlook Web access.
- Creating Distribution Groups in Mail Server. Configuring e-mail accounts using MS-Outlook
   -2007.
- Configuring and administrating firewall. Load balancing and writing app rules, writing, and applying policies.
- VPN and tunneling.

### **Education:**

- **B.tech(2009-2013)** in Information Technology with 61% at Kshatriya College of Engineering, Armoor.
- Intermediate (2009) with an aggregate of 50% in Trinity Junior College, Karimnagar.
- **SSC** (2007) with an aggregate 67% in Vivekananda Vidyanikethan High School, Metpally.

### **Additional Qualifications:**

- CCNA
- MCSE
- Fortinet Certified Associate in Cybersecurity.
- Attend various IT seminars for knowledge improvement and networking.
- AZURE 900

### **PERSONAL DETAILS:**

Name :Dilip Kumar. Nune

Date of Birth : 22-07-1992

Father's Name : Laxman. N

Nationality : Indian

Languages Known : English, Telugu and Hindi

Permanent Address : S/o. N. LAXMAN

D.No: 5-105, Yamapour, Ibrahimpatnam,

Jagithyal, PIN:505450.

Place: Hyderabad (DILIPKUMAR.N)